Finding Aid for the Grantland Rice Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Grantland Rice Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0364
19.26 linear_feet
Biography
Grantland Rice (1880-1954) was born in Murfreesboro, Tennessee, the son of Bolling H. and Beulah Grantland Rice. Educated at Vanderbilt University, he went to work as a reporter for the Nashville News in 1901. He also worked at Forester Magazine (1901), the Atlanta Journal (1902-1904), the Cleveland News (1905), the Nashville Tennessean (1906-1910), the New York Mail (1911-1914), and the New York Tribune (1914-1930).
In 1918 and 1919 Rice served as First Lieutenant with 115th Regiment F.A., 30th Division, U.S. Army with the American Expeditionary Force in France.
In 1930, his column "The Sportlight" became nationally syndicated and ran until his death in 1954. Rice was also the author of Songs of the Stalwart (1917), Sportlights of 1923, Sportlights of 1924, Songs of the Open (1924), and Only the Brave (1941).
On 11 April 1906, Grantland Rice was married to Katharine Hollis, and they had a daughter, Florence Davenport.
Scope and Content Note
The Papers of Grantland Rice (1905-1966) are comprised of 19.26 linear feet and include his Writings, Correspondence, Personal and Biographical Materials, Photographs, Subject Files, Souvenirs, and Memorabilia.
- Correspondence - Outgoing (Box 1)
  39 items include 2 typed originals, 3 copies (2 carbon, 1 photo), 1 mimeo., and 32 telegrams, 4 are addressed to Kate Hollis Rice; most have to do with selection of Football All-Americans.
- Correspondence - Incoming
  462 items include 83 holograph letters, 241 typed original letters, 18 copies (12 carbon, 6 photo + retyped), 70 telegrams, 10 mimeo., printed etc., 32 greeting cards, 3 postcards, and 3 misc. 347 items are addressed to GR, 74 to Kate Hollis Rice (KHR), and 41 to other people. 3 illegible signatures, 9 incomplete signatures, 4 false signatures, 7 items unsigned. Included are 82 letters from Football All-Americans sent in connection with "This Is Your Life" radio program, December, 1948. See itemized list of these letters, and indices to outgoing and incoming correspondence, below.
  - Aarons, Mrs. Ellis, 16 Oct 1942; (1) (Box 1)
  - Ainger, F.B. Jr., 13 May 1920; (1) (Box 1)
  - Aisenbrey, E.J., 20 May 1940; (1) (Box 1)
  - Akers, Sam, 2 Nov 1962 (to Dave Camerer); (1) (Box 1)
  - Albert, Frank, 28 Dec 1948; (1) (Box 1)
  - Alberti, Jules, 14 July 1954 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Aldrich, Ki, 9 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Alexander, W.A., 10 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 1)
  - American Golfer, 10 Feb 1916; (1) (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Ernfred, 19 Sept 1956 (to Robert McGaw); (1) (Box 1)
  - Anderson, John L., 12 Nov 1951; (1) (Box 1)
  - Aubrey, George W., 1 Feb 1923; (1) (Box 1)
  - Bagshaw, Enoch, 17 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, Buss B, n.d.; (1) (Box 1)
  - Baley, Archie J., 6 Dec 1943 (2 -- 1 to E.Z. Black), n.d. (2); (4) (Box 1)
  - Barkas, Bert, 11 Jan 1951; (1) (Box 1)
  - Bartlett, Michael, 14 July 1954 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Barton, Bruce, 4 Jan 1950, 12 Mar 1951 (to Charles McCabe); (2) (Box 1)
  - Barton, George A., 30 Dec 1941, 20 Jan 1942; (2) (Box 1)
  - Batchelor, E.A., 19 Nov 1925 (2), 21 Nov 1925; (3) (Box 1)
  - Bearg, Ernest E., 9 Nov 1925, 11 Nov 1925; (2) (Box 1)
  - believer of fair play, A, n.d.; (1) (Box 1)
  - Berger, George, 28 Nov 1930; (1) (Box 1)
  - Bertelli, Angelo, 4 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Best, S., 16 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 1)
  - Black, E.Z. - see Baley (Box 1)
  - Blaik, Red, 14 July 1954 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Blandin, Ernest E., 10 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Boeringer, Arthur "Bud", 1 Feb 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Bond, Roland S., 2 Nov 1938; (1) (Box 1)
  - Botsford, Florence H., 1 June 1920; (1) (Box 1)
  - Bottari, Vic, 10 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Bowers, Frank K., 13 July 1922; (1) (Box 1)
  - Boyd, Joe M., 13 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Brackenridge, Anne and Gavin, n.d. (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Branscomb, Harvie, 23 July 1954 (to Bob McGaw), n.d.; (2) (Box 1)
    (to Bob, signed H.B.) - see also Milburn, Wilson
  - Brewer, C.L., 17 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 1)
  - Brooke, George H., 28 Dec 19??; (1) (Box 1)
  - Brougham, Royal, 17 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 1)
  - Brown, Innis, 14 July 1954 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Brown, Warren W., 18 Nov 1925, n.d.; (2) (Box 1)
  - Brush, Graham M., n.d. (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Burnett, W.E. & Co., 5 Mar 1929 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Butler, Bill H., 22 Mar 1833 - see Illegible signatures; (1) (Box 1)
  - Butz, J.S.G., 11 Dec 1951; (1) (Box 1)
  - Byrnes, George, 9 Sept 1947, 29 Nov 1948, 7 July 1950; (3) (Box 1)
  - Cain, Cullen, 8 Jan 1950; (1) (Box 1)
  - Cain, Harry P., 27 Nov 1950; (1) (Box 1)
  - Callahan, North, n.d. (to Catherine Mecca); (1) (Box 1)
  - Camerer, David, 21 Apr 1955 (to Fred Russell) 22 June 19??, n.d. (10 - 2 to Gr, 8 to KHR) - see also Akers; (12) (Box 1)
  - Campbell, Heyworth, 17 Dec 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Campbell, Phil D., 7 Mar 1946; (1) (Box 1)
  - Campbell, Sara Ann, 25 Dec 1934; (1) (Box 1)
  - Carey, Bill and Ocean, (1) (Box 1)
  - Carmichael, O.C., 5 Feb 1941 (to Fred Russell) - see also Russell; (1) (Box 1)
  - Carney, Peter P., 16 Mar 1922; (1) (Box 1)
  - Carter, Amon G., 14 July 1954 (to KHR), 20 July 1954 (to KHR from sec'y, Katrine Deakins); (2) (Box 1)
  - Carter, Charles Francis, 20 Mar 1920; (1) (Box 1)
  - Cason, Charles, 17 Nov 195? (to Vanderbilt Alumnus); (1) (Box 1)
  - Champion, Jim(?) and family, (1) (Box 1)
  - Chase, Daniel, 21 Jan 1957; (1) (Box 1)
  - Chenery, William L., 23 Mar 1942 - see also Perrin; (1) (Box 1)
  - Christman, Paul, 3 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Clayton, Spencer W., 18 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 1)
  - Cleary, Paul H., 22 Dec 1948; (1) (Box 1)
  - Close, Virginia L., 12 Dec 1959 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Cobb, Tyrus R., 5 May 1952; (1) (Box 1)
  - Coe, Charles Francis, 22 June 1934; (1) (Box 1)
  - Cohane, Tim, 26 Feb 1959 (to KHR) - see also McGaw; (1) (Box 1)
  - Condon, Betty and Lucky, 2 Oct 1940 (to KHR) (see also Incomplete Signatures); (1) (Box 1)
  - Conley, H.H., 16 Feb 1947; (1) (Box 1)
  - Conlon, Scoop, 28 June 19??; (1) (Box 1)
  - Cooke, Edmund Vance, 2 Aug 1907; (1) (Box 1)
  - Corbett, Jim, 6 Dec 1953; (1) (Box 1)
  - Cornwell, Dean, n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 1)
  - Cox, James M., 14 July 1954 (to GR family); (1) (Box 1)
  - Crosby, Bing, 19 Mar 1947 (to KHR), 20 Jan 1955 (to KHR, from sec'y, Rosemary Carroll), n.d. (Christmas card); (3) (Box 1)
  - Crowninshield, Frank, n.d. (Christmas card, to KHR) - see also Lardner, Tunney; (1) (Box 1)
  - Cullum, R.A., 19 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 1)
  - Cunningham, Bill, 9 Dec 1959 (to KHR, from sec'y, Jane Whalen); (1) (Box 1)
  - Danieli, Averell E., 4 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Davies, H.R., 17 Jan 1927; (1) (Box 1)
  - Davis, Glenn, 12 Apr 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Davis, Howard, 20 Feb 1926; (1) (Box 1)
  - Davis, Smith, n.d.; (1) (Box 1)
  - Demaret, Jimmy, 15 Apr 19??; (1) (Box 1)
  - Dempsey, Jack, Nov 1955; (1) (Box 1)
  - Desmond, Thomas C., 6 Mar 1950; (1) (Box 1)
  - Diehl, Carl H., n.d.; (1) (Box 1)
  - Dodd, Bobby, 25 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Doty, Edith M. - see also Epes, 15 Nov 1934; (1) (Box 1)
  - Donchess, Joseph C., 3 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Duden, Dick, 20 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Dudley, Bruce, 1 Nov 1948; (1) (Box 1)
  - Dunken, Flora, 12 June 1947; (1) (Box 1)
  - Eckersall, Walter H., 15 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 1)
  - Editor, Managing - see Wheeler (Box 1)
  - Editors, Sports, of Daily Newspapers - see No Signature (Box 1)
  - Egan, Lee, 20 July 19?? (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Ellard, Roscoe, 15 Dec 1953; (1) (Box 1)
  - Elliott, Don, 6 Nov 1963 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Ely, Lawrence S., 14 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Epes, Horace, 16 May 1934 (to Edith M. Doty); (1) (Box 1)
  - Evans, Arthur L., n.d.; (1) (Box 1)
  - Evans, Charles Jr., 2 Nov 1923; (1) (Box 1)
  - Evans, Jasper, 14 Feb 1948; (1) (Box 1)
  - Farley, James A., 10 Nov 1950, 4 May 1951, n.d. (Christmas card); (3) (Box 1)
  - Farrow, Ruth, 25 July 1954 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Feathers, Beattie, 15 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Fenimore, Bob, 11 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Ferraro, John, 23 Dec 1948; (1) (Box 1)
  - Fesler, Wesley, 13 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Filley, Patrick J., 7 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Fitzgerald, Ed, 17 Jan 1952 (to Catherine Mecca); (1) (Box 1)
  - Fleeson, Edgar T., 21 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 1)
  - Fleming, Ian, 16 July 1954 (to John Wheeler); (1) (Box 1)
  - Fletcher, Harry P., 15 Apr 1921; (1) (Box 1)
  - Folmar, Wilson, 19 July 19?? (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Fowler, Gene, 11 Oct 1933, 12 Mar 1948; (2) (Box 1)
  - Franco, Ed, 26 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Freeman, Donald - see Tunney (Box 1)
  - Friedman, Anna, 16 Nov 1954 (to GR family); (1) (Box 1)
  - Fullerton, Hugh, 11 Dec 19??; (1) (Box 1)
  - Furay, James H., 25 Nov 1946; (1) (Box 1)
  - Geffer, M.M., 11 May 1955 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Giesler, Jerry and Ruth, n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 1)
  - Gillespie, Jake, n.d. (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Gilmer, Harry, 7 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Glassgow, Willis A., 5 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Gleeves(?), "Scoop", 28 Oct 1925; (1) (Box 1)
  - Godchaux, Frank A., 3 Dec 1943, 4 Dec 1943; (2) (Box 1)
  - Goetz, Harry M., 17 Jan 1930 - see also Johnson; (1) (Box 1)
  - Goldberg, Rube and Irma, 18 Oct 1950, Christmas 1962 (to KHR), n.d. (to KHR); (3) (Box 1)
  - Goldberg, Marshall, 15 Feb 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Goldman, Herman, n.d.; (1) (Box 1)
  - Governali, Paul, 4 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Graham, - see Russell (Box 1)
  - Grant, Madison, 30 Apr 1924; (1) (Box 1)
  - Grayson, Robert H., 7 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Greene, Marc T., 25 Sept (1950 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Griffith, Clark C., 14 July 1954 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Gudger, Francis A., 24 Apr 1947; (1) (Box 1)
  - Grisham F., n.d. (to W. Wasson); (1) (Box 1)
  - Guild Hall, n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 1)
  - Hagen, Walter, 30 Oct 1954 (to Ed Sullivan); (1) (Box 1)
  - Hanna, 21 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 1)
  - Harding, Warren G., 9 Mar 1921, 17 Mar 1921, 16 Apr 1921; (3) (Box 1)
  - Harmon, Torn, 19 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Hastings, Harry, 2 Oct 1950; (1) (Box 1)
  - Hawley, Jess, 18 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 1)
  - Heath, E.M., 18 Nov 1918; (1) (Box 1)
  - Hebert, Bob, 5 Jan 19??; (1) (Box 1)
  - Heisman, John W., 22 Mar 1929; (1) (Box 1)
  - Helis, William G. Jr., n.d.; (1) (Box 1)
  - Heyn, Ernie, 29 Dec 1948; (1) (Box 1)
  - Hill, Harry W., 5 Dec 1950; (1) (Box 1)
  - Hinkle, Carl C., 27 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Hitchcock, Jimmy, 11 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Hogan, Valerie and Ben, 13 July 1949 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Holden, Albon W., 10 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 1)
  - Holland, "Bud", (1) (Box 1)
  - Holzworth, John M., 20 Feb 1932; (1) (Box 1)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar, 5 July 1951, 25 Aug 1954 (to KHR); (2) (Box 1)
  - Houser, Victor Carl, 10 July 1955 (to Vanderbilt University) - see also McGaw; (1) (Box 1)
  - Houston, Frank K., 15 July 1954 (to E.E. Wilson); (1) (Box 1)
  - Houston, Lindell, 8 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Howard, Roy W., 16 Jan 1950; (1) (Box 1)
  - Humble, Weldon G., 26 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Huntington, Ellery C. Jr., 18 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 1)
  - Hutson, Don, 7 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Hyman, Dick, 5 Dee 1951; (1) (Box 1)
  - James, Sidney L. - see McGaw (Box 1)
  - Johns, W.C., 13 July 1954 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Nunnally, 13 Jan 1950 (to Harry M. Goetz); (1) (Box 1)
  - Johnston, Hattie Belle, 18 July 1954 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Jones, T.A.D., 17 Nov 1925, n.d.; (2) (Box 1)
  - Kaer, Morton, 27 Dec 1948; (1) (Box 1)
  - Kelland, Clarence Budington, 14 Feb 1954; (1) (Box 1)
  - Keller, O.B., 8 Jan 1942, 30 June 1943; (2) (Box 1)
  - Kelley, Robert F., n.d. (to KHR) (see also Incomplete Signatures); (1) (Box 1)
  - Kieran, John, 11 Jan 1950, n.d.; (2) (Box 1)
  - Kieran, Margaret Ford, n.d.; (1) (Box 1)
  - Kilpatrick, John Reed, n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 1)
  - Kiner, Ralph and Nancy, n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 1)
  - Knight, Harold D., 19 July 1954 (to Robert A. McGaw); (1) (Box 1)
  - Koretz, David, 13 Jan 1959 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Krause, Ed, 14 July 1954 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Krueger, Ockie, 7 Aug 1951; (1) (Box 1)
  - Kuhlrnan, A.F. - see McGaw (Box 1)
  - Kully, Barney M., n.d.; (1) (Box 1)
  - Kutner, Mai, 18 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - La Marca, Albert, 15 May 1951; (1) (Box 1)
  - Lanier, Charles Frank, 1 Jan 19?? (wedding invitation); (1) (Box 1)
  - Lardner, Ring, 20 Dec 1924 (to Frank Crowninshield), 23 Dec 1926; 3 envelopes without letters (l with check for $200 to GB from RL, 11 Nov 1931) (see also Incomplete Signatures); (5) (Box 1)
  - Lee, Virginia Getty, 20 Aug 1956 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Lepper, Robert J., 1 May 1958 (to KHR); (1) (Box 1)
  - Levine, Henry, 10 May 1949; (1) (Box 1)
  - Lilly, Herbert D., 27 Dec 1934; (1) (Box 1)
  - Little, Lou, 14 May 1945, 2 May 1951; (2) (Box 1)
  - Little, S. George, 16 Dec 1944; (1) (Box 1)
  - Lujack, Johnny, 5 Feb 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Lund, Francis L., 17 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Mack, Charlie, n.d. ("Bacardi Mixture" recipe); (1) (Box 2)
  - Mancha, Vaughn, 17 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - MacPhail, Larry and Jean, n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 2)
  - Marshall, W.p., 15 July (1954) (to John Wheeler); (1) (Box 2)
  - Mastrangelo, John, 17 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Maxwell, Lee W., 21 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 2)
  - McCabe, Charles - see Bruce Barton (Box 2)
  - McClelland, William D., 24 Jan 1945; (1) (Box 2)
  - McFadden, J. Banks, 4 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - McGaw, Robert A., 19 Nov 1954 (3 - to Tim Cohane, Sidney L. James, Jack Mohr), 14 July 1953 (to Victor Carl Houser), 15 July 1955 (2 - to KHR and A.F. Kuhlman), 25 May 1936 (to KHR) - see also Anderson, Branscomb, Knight, Mohr, Wakelee; (7) (Box 2)
  - McGill, John T., 2 July 1920; (1) (Box 2)
  - McGugin, Dan E., 10 Nov 1925, 17 Nov 1925, 14 Sept 1934; (3) (Box 2)
  - Mclntyre, R.S., 16 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 2)
  - McMillan, Ed, 24 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - McNulty, John, n.d.; (1) (Box 2)
  - Mecca, Catherine, 5 Jan 1949 (to KHR), 26 Feb 1951 (to KHR) - see also Callahan, Fitzgerald; (2) (Box 2)
  - Megrick, Owen, 22 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 2)
  - Mencken, H.L., 10 Mar 1948, 12 Mar 1948; (2) (Box 2)
  - Milburn, Devereux Jr., 17 Dec 1954 (to Harvie Branscomb); (1) (Box 2)
  - Miller, Creighton E., 13 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Miller, Don C., 25 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Minisi, Anthony A., 7 Feb 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Mohr, Jack, 23 Nov 1954 (to Robert McGaw) - see also McGaw; (1) (Box 2)
  - Monett, Ed, n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 2)
  - Monsky, Leroy, 12 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Edward Small, n.d, (Christmas card); (1) (Box 2)
  - Morgan, Clay and Ellen, n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 2)
  - Morrison, Bob, 26 Mar 1942 (to R.W. Yocum); (1) (Box 2)
  - Morson, Larom B., 16 Nov 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Nagurski, Bronco, 19 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Nash, Tom, 17 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Neilson, Rutgers, 18 Aug 1942; (1) (Box 2)
  - Nevers, Ernie, 6 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Nisonger, Earl and Francesca, n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 2)
  - Norris, Charles and Kathleen, 1939 (Christmas card); (1) (Box 2)
  - O'Brien, David, 19 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - O'Brien, Morgan J., n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 2)
  - O'Hara, John, n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 2)
  - Osborne, Nelson C., 14 Nov 1951; (1) (Box 2)
  - O'Toole, William D., 5 Jan 1954; (1) (Box 2)
  - Ouide(?), CE., n.d.; (1) (Box 2)
  - Owens, Freeman H., 20 May 1954; (1) (Box 2)
  - Parcells, C.C.(?), 27 Dec 1917; (1) (Box 2)
  - Parker, Dan, n.d. (note on unsigned letter to DP, forwarded to GR); (1) (Box 2)
  - Patterson, Paul, Dec 1951; (1) (Box 2)
  - Pegler, Westbrook and Julie, Dec 1938 (Christmas card); (1) (Box 2)
  - Pemberton, Brock and Margaret, n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 2)
  - Perkins, Albert R., 4 Feb 1947; (1) (Box 2)
  - Perrin, T.O., 30 May 1942 (to William L. Chenery); (1) (Box 2)
  - Perry, Lawrence, 21 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 2)
  - Phelps, William Lyon, 12 May 1934; (1) (Box 2)
  - Pickens, Champ, 18 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 2)
  - Powers, Francis J., 19 Nov 1925, n.d.; (2) (Box 2)
  - Pratt, John Lowell, 20 Oct 1959 (to KHR); (1) (Box 2)
  - Prentice-Hall, Inc, 18 Apr 1939; (1) (Box 2)
  - Pryor family, n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 2)
  - Purcell, Jack, n.d.; (1) (Box 2)
  - Purvis, Duane, 10 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Quatse, Jesse, 5 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Reilly, J.A., 15 Feb 1945; (1) (Box 2)
  - Reinhard, Bob, 28 Dec 1948; (1) (Box 2)
  - Rentner, Ernest J., 6 Jan 1948; (1) (Box 2)
  - Reynolds, G.E., 9 Mar 1932; (1) (Box 2)
  - Rice, Boiling, 4 Apr 1950; (1) (Box 2)
  - Rhea, Hugh M., 2 Feb 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Rice, Albert Hughes, and Frierson Hopkins Rice, 22 Oct 1950, 6 Jan 1951; (2) (Box 2)
  - Rice, Florence, 28 Nov 1936 (to KHR), n.d. (to KHR), 19 Dec 1955 (to KHR); 4 ms verses, 6 greeting cards (to GR and KHR); (13) (Box 2)
  - Rice, Katherine Hollis, 31 Oct 1962 (to Rube Samuelson); (1) (Box 2)
  - Rice, Lucy (Mrs. B.H.), n.d. (to KHR); (1) (Box 2)
  - Rich, Charles A., 26 Sept 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Rickey, Branch, 30 Sept 1950; (1) (Box 2)
  - Roberts, Roy A., 14 July (1954) (to KHR); (1) (Box 2)
  - Rockne, Knute, 10 Nov 1925, 19 Nov 1925; (2) (Box 2)
  - Rodgers, I.E., 16 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 2)
  - Roosevelt, Duncan, 9 June 1923, 28 Apr 1924; (2) (Box 2)
  - Roper, Bill, 10 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 2)
  - Runyon, Damon, n.d. (to Fran----); (1) (Box 2)
  - Russell, Fred, 3 Feb 1941 (to O.C. Carmichael), 28 Mar 1955 (to KHR), 9 May 1956 (to KHR), 6 Nov 1958 (to KHR), 19 July 1962 (to KHR), ---- Graham) -- see also Camerer, Carmichael; (6) (Box 2)
  - Ruszhay, Tomas B., 2 Mar 1942; (1) (Box 2)
  - Salsinger, H.G., 20 Nov 1925, 21 Nov 1925; (2) (Box 2)
  - Samuelson, Rube -- see K.H. Rice (Box 2)
  - Sarkkinen, Esco, 19 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Sauer, George H., 3 Feb 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Scull, Paul T., 24 Feb 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Sculley, John Jr., 11 Dec 1936; (1) (Box 2)
  - Seton, Harold, 7 Nov 1934; (1) (Box 2)
  - Seviachy (?), Bill, 4 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Shaver, Gaius, 21 Dec 1948; (1) (Box 2)
  - Shively, Bernie A., 14 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Shor, Toots, 26 Sept 1951, 19 May 1953, 5 Aug 1953; (3) (Box 2)
  - Shuster, W. Morgan, 1 Feb 1921; (1) (Box 2)
  - Sington, Fred, 5 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Skladany, Joseph P., 13 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Smith, Andrew, 19 Nov 1925, n.d.; (2) (Box 2)
  - Smith, Bruce, 7 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Smith, Ernie F., 28 Dec 1948; (1) (Box 2)
  - Smith, John H., 13 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Smith, John P. "Clipper", 6 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Smith, Orland F., 3 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Smith, lied and Kay, 14 July 1954 (to KHR); (1) (Box 2)
  - Snow, John B., 11 June 1936; (1) (Box 2)
  - Sonnenblick(?), Ira J., 17 Nov 1923; (1) (Box 2)
  - Spears, C.W., 18 Nov 1923; (1) (Box 2)
  - Speck, Rose M., 13 Feb 1932; (1) (Box 2)
  - Sports editors of daily newspapers -- see No Signature (Box 2)
  - Steffy, Joseph B., Jr., 3 Jan 1948; (1) (Box 2)
  - Stevens, Edward A., 9 Dec 1934; (1) (Box 2)
  - Strassmann, Tony, 3 Apr 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Strong, Ken, 17 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Stuhldreher, Harry, 14 July 1934 (to KHR), n.d.; (2) (Box 2)
  - Suffridge, R.L., 11 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Sukey (?), Steven, (18 Jan 1949); (1) (Box 2)
  - Sullivan, Ed -- see Hagen (Box 2)
  - Summerfelt, Milton F., 17 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Tarkington, Booth, 28 Nov 1933; (1) (Box 2)
  - Taylor, Henry J., 5 Jan 1950; (1) (Box 2)
  - Taylor, J.W., 14 Nov 1949, 9 Dec 1949; (2) (Box 2)
  - Thomas, Charles Allen, 14 Oct 1940; (1) (Box 2)
  - Trautman, George M., 15 July 1954 (to KHR); (1) (Box 2)
  - Trippe, Juan and Betty, n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 2)
  - Tunney, Gene, 19 Apr 1929 (to Frank Crowninshield), 9 May 1929 (to Donald Freeman); (2) (Box 2)
  - Vanderbilt University -- see Houser (Box 2)
  - Van Surdam, Henderson E., 22 Dec 19?? (to KHR); (1) (Box 2)
  - Vessels(?), Billy, n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 2)
  - Vogel, Jerry, 30 Oct 1947; (1) (Box 2)
  - Wade, Wallace, 10 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 2)
  - Wakelee, Arthur H., 10 Feb 1956 (to Robert McGaw); (1) (Box 2)
  - Walker, Mickey, 11 Jan 1954; (1) (Box 2)
  - Wallace, C.B., 2 Nov 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Walsh, Christy, 25 Oct 1933; (1) (Box 2)
  - Warburton, Irvine "Cotton", 28 Dec 1948; (1) (Box 2)
  - Warner, G.L., 22 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 2)
  - Warner, Glenn S., 9 Nov 1925; (1) (Box 2)
  - Webb, Thompson, 7 Jan 1935; (1) (Box 2)
  - Weech, William A., 17 Nov 1933; (1) (Box 2)
  - Welch, Gilbert L., 5 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Weiler, Jac, 27 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Wells, Captain -- see Illegible Signatures (Box 2)
  - Wells, W.H., 28 Feb 1930; (1) (Box 2)
  - Werblin, David A., 4 May 1951; (1) (Box 2)
  - Wesson, Al, 24 May 1949, 29 Mar 1950, 30 Apr 1951; (3) (Box 2)
  - Wesson, Frannie, n.d. (to KHR); (1) (Box 2)
  - Wheeler, John N., 26 Oct 1935 (to the Managing Editor), 19 July 1954 (to KHR) -- see also Cox, Fleming, Marshall; Incomplete Signatures, Herbert; (2) (Box 2)
  - Whitaker, Mrs. Ben F., 15 July 1954 (to KHR); (1) (Box 2)
  - Whitlock, Fred, 2 June 1933; (1) (Box 2)
  - Whitmire, Don, 18 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Wickhorst, Frank H., 10 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Wilce, Jack W., 12 Nov 1925, 18 Nov 1925; (2) (Box 2)
  - Wilkinson, Tim and Frances, n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 2)
  - Williams, Robert D., Jr., 4 Nov 1955 (to KHR, from sec'y, Dorothy B. Porter); (1) (Box 2)
  - Wilson, E.E., 13 Feb 1952 (to Harvie Branscomb) -- see also Houston; (1) (Box 2)
  - Wilson, Robert, 24 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Winkin, John, 27 Apr 1948; (1) (Box 2)
  - Wood, Sidney B. Jr., 30 Mar 1955 (to KHR); (1) (Box 2)
  - Woodruff, Bob, Dec 1949 (Christmas card), 14 July 1954 (to KHR); (2) (Box 2)
  - Woodward, Russel and Mimi, n.d. (Christmas card); (1) (Box 2)
  - Wyatt, Bowden, 14 Jan 1949; (1) (Box 2)
  - Wylie, Edward A.B., n.d. (frag.); (1) (Box 2)
  - Yocum, R.W. -- see Morrison (Box 2)
  - Yost, Fielding H., 10 Nov 1925, 20 Nov 1925; (2) (Box 2)
  - Young, B.E., 17 Aug 1907; (1) (Box 2)
  - Young, Louis A., 17 Nov 1925, 18 Nov 1925; (2) (Box 2)
  - Youngsteadt, R.W. "Gno", 31 Aug 1948; (1) (Box 2)
  - Zerby, Doris, 29 Dec 1948; (1) (Box 2)
  - Zuppke, Robert C., 11 Nov 1925, 18 Nov 1925, 19 Nov 1925; (3) (Box 2)
  - Illegible signatures (Box 2, Folder 29)
    To Bill H. Butler from ----, 22 Mar 1833
    To Captain Wells from ----, 27 Feb 1930
    To Grantland(Rice)from ----, n.d. (Hotel New Yorker letterhead)
  - Incomplete signatures; False and No signatures (Box 2, Folder 30-33)
    To Granny from F.C., 9 May (1938) (perhaps F---- Condon) fragment, n.d, from Bob K. (probably Bob Kelley)
    To Mrs. Rice,from Esther, Sadday (sic) (from internal evidence, possibly Ring Lardner,--i.e. blue typewriter ink, reference to June Moon)
    To John M. Wheeler from Herbert, 13 July (1954)
    To Grantland from Julian, 15 Nov 1925
    To Granny from Marian, 29 Apr 1949 (Life magazine letterhead)
    To Granny from Mark, 2 June 1949 (20th-century Fox letterhead)
    To Kate from Mildred, Saturday
    To Grannie from R----, n.d. (New Yorker magazine letterhead; ref. to Mencken)
    To Katie from Broken (Heart), n.d. (Knickerbocker Club note)
    To Grant from Old Dear (Deac?), 21 Aug 1934
    To Sir from J. Fenimore Cooper, n.d. (on Mrs. Grantland Rice's stationery, but also very possibly by Ring Lardner)
    To Grant Rice from The Jigger King, n.d. (RHD initial stationery)
    To Mr. Rice from ---- (U.S. Naval Academy), 8 January 1949
    Draft of letter to Sports Editors, July 1955
    3 items dated 12 Nov(1925), 22 Nov 1925, 29 Dec 1948
    2 items unsigned and undated
  - Correspondence, incoming -- letters from All-American football players